Marty ! Doc !
What happened to the DeLorean ?
Remember, at the end of BTTF 3 it has been crushed by a train
It didn't passed technical inspection anymore
and this one can drive up to 120 km
it's way enough when one travel ... in time !
But, why this outfit ?
Oh damn, you're right : Marty,
We have to fix the future !
Future ? What's up with future ?
I'm just back from year 2042
at a time earth has been devastated
By nuclear weapons
What ?
Yes, a technical bug
in computers chips
allowed North Corea to hack
Chineese nuclear system
(which was still running a pirated Windows XP)
and in 2022, BOOM!
At this time, Trump (just being re-elected) decided to hit back
and Poutine ...
anyway, there's nothing left
What can we do ?
Need to fix this problem from source
prevent this bug being introduced in processors
How ?
This bug has been introduced in 1988
In 1988 !?
Yes, due to backward compatibility
this implementation detail
is still present in 2022's CPUs.
The hardware architect, who introduced the bug by mistake,
was working on this topic
in 1988
and this when we need to act
You're the Doc, Doc
Where can we find this "architect" ?
He made a lecture at BreizhCamp
not far away
hum, not far in space, but
in time it was 30 years ago
anyway, distances
in space-time continuum
are very abstract concepts
As you say so, Doc.
Don't spend more time.
Put on these 80's closes, I remove this
hurry up !
We don't need to hurry actually
Bu not doing so, this movie would be so boring !
Spate-time convector will
get us back in 1988. I'm configuring it
to arrive on first day of BreizhCamp conference
on March 28th 1988
Let's put on our seatbelt !
No need for security Marty!
Where we go we don't need root !
(road "route" in french == "root")
Hello
can I take your name for badges ?
Mar...
Mark Zuckerberg ! and I'm Linus Torvalds
ok, please 50 francs for entrance
Oups, seems I made a mistake with your name
Never mind
How exciting, isn't it ?
Let's check this place,
we'll be here in two minutes
Waou, that's high définition !
Yes indeed, it's Super VGA,
up to 1024x768 with 16 colours
It's perfect match for a graphic workstation
Is it free ?
hum, not really...
Hello sir !
Are you a developer ?
What ?
Do you know our development environment
DosDEV ?
It's a highly productive environnement
up to 10 time faster
than what you've been used to
I give you the brochure
don't hesitate to give it a try
OMG, one did crazy things in 80's
F***, this game is a piece of shit !
Seem they where drunk or drugged coding it
I'll become crazy with it
or maybe an angry video game nerd?
McFly !!!
did you fix the Street Fighter arcade in the cafetaria ?
Not yet Biff, that's a complex job you know ...
as you overthrow Coke on it ...
And how do you expect me
to train for the challenge
if you don't fix the arcade ?
I'll do it today, I promise.
... Dad is a Nerd !
Hey Marty, here you are
Sorry for that, would prefer you don't see him
but you know, in 2018
beeing a geek will be cool ... surprisingly
If you say so, Doc
Let's go
... and with the new memory model
and unified cache we will get
80x386 architecture way beyong
it's initial capacity
We get execution speed moslty doubled !
Come and ask him any questions
while I'm fixing his documents
Hello, interesting lecture. I wonder ...
how far will you get this new generation
what's its execution frequency ?
25 MHz ! and we even have in labs
a 33 MHz prototype
interesting ...
And with 8 ko integrated cache
and a 32 bits communication bus
we will have access to huge resources
Imagine:
We could even go beyong the 640k limit :)
but .. what about heat ?
You're right, with incredibly fine engraving
at only 1 micron, this becomes an issue
We are looking for workarounds
maybe will need a heat dissipator
oh right, thanks
I'm done Marty, we can leave
McFly, McFly what's the hell are you doing. Learn programming ?
Not fixing the Arcade ?
But you know ...
Hope we haven't altered the space-time continuum
Hello, hello, anybody home?
Think, McFly. Think!
Do you realize what would happen
if I start the challenge
without being trained enough ? Want me to be a looser ?
Want me to be look like an idiot during challenge ?
Is it what you're looking for ?
Of course not, Biff
now I wouldn't want that to happen.
Hey sir, you left this on the floor
Oh thanks.
Great game, you'll get lot's of fun with it
Hey McFly, I'll train on this one
waiting for you to fix the arcade
I'll work on it first thing tomorrow, alright?
Oh, McFly, your shoe's untied.
Don't be so gullible, McFly.
Tell me Doc, this Intel Architect
How did you know it was speaking at BreizhCamp ?
Matry,
Best speakers all come to BreizhCamp !